const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following conditions can be treated with the use of topical atropine?","answers":[{"option":"Scleritis","bool":false},{"option":"Uveitis","bool":true},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Refractive error","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is the laser used for treating posterior capsular opacification in adults?","answers":[{"option":"Argon laser","bool":false},{"option":"Excimer laser","bool":false},{"option":"Holmium laser","bool":false},{"option":"Nd-YAG laser","bool":true},{"option":"Femtosecond laser","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Probing is the recommended treatment for congenital nasolacrimal duct obstruction. What is the age of the infant after which probing should be performed?","answers":[{"option":"12 months","bool":true},{"option":"6 years","bool":false},{"option":"6 months","bool":false},{"option":"2 years","bool":false},{"option":"18 months","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is responsible for aqueous humor secretion?","answers":[{"option":"Ciliary body","bool":true},{"option":"Retina","bool":false},{"option":"Iris","bool":false},{"option":"Choroid","bool":false},{"option":"Lens","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is the best time to treat bilateral dense congenital cataracts?","answers":[{"option":"Immediately after birth","bool":false},{"option":"Within first 3 weeks of age","bool":false},{"option":"At a young age","bool":false},{"option":"At 1 year","bool":false},{"option":"4 to 10 weeks of age","bool":true}]},{"id":5,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is a common ophthalmologic side effect of systemic steroid therapy?","answers":[{"option":"Hemangioma","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior uveitis","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior subcapsular cataract","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior uveitis","bool":false},{"option":"Scleritis","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most prevalent cause of blindness?","answers":[{"option":"Diabetic retinopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Cataract","bool":true},{"option":"Corneal opacities","bool":false},{"option":"Aphakia","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following statements is true about basal cell carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"It is the least common malignancy","bool":false},{"option":"It is non metastasizing","bool":true},{"option":"It arises from nerve sheath","bool":false},{"option":"It is a benign tumor","bool":false},{"option":"It is not locally invasive","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most common surgical method for treating myopia?","answers":[{"option":"Clear lens extraction","bool":false},{"option":"Radical Keratotomy (RK)","bool":false},{"option":"Laser in Situ Keratomileusis (LASIK)","bool":true},{"option":"Photorefractive Keratectomy (PRK)","bool":false},{"option":"Laser Epithelial Keratomileusis (LASEK)","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"What is the most common cause of cataracts in young adults?","answers":[{"option":"Senility","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":true},{"option":"Diabetes mellitus","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following disease presents with the characteristic T-sign on ultrasonography?","answers":[{"option":"Cataract due to diabetes","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior scleritis","bool":true},{"option":"Congenital glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior scleritis","bool":false},{"option":"Episcleritis","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"What is the age at which pathological myopia begins?","answers":[{"option":"50- 70 years","bool":false},{"option":"15-20 years","bool":false},{"option":"5-10 years","bool":true},{"option":"25-50 years","bool":false},{"option":"30-40 years","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is not true regarding retrobulbar optic neuritis?","answers":[{"option":"It is a painful condition","bool":false},{"option":"Color vision is affected","bool":false},{"option":"Vision begins to improve spontaneously","bool":false},{"option":"Papillitis is present","bool":true},{"option":"Vision loss is subacute developing over 2-7 days","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Where does the light focus in cases of hypermetropia?","answers":[{"option":"Image is not formed","bool":false},{"option":"Behind the retina","bool":true},{"option":"Image is formed on the center but the brain does not perceive it","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple points on the retina","bool":false},{"option":"In front of the retina","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"What is the most common type of congenital glaucoma?","answers":[{"option":"Juvenile glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary infantile glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Infantile glaucoma","bool":true},{"option":"Secondary juvenile glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"True congenital glaucoma","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"What is the most common systemic cause of congenital cataracts?","answers":[{"option":"Hallerman-Streiff sydrome","bool":false},{"option":"Lowe syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Nance-Horan syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Edward syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Down syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"What is the most common post-operative complication of a congenital cataract?","answers":[{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Strabismus","bool":false},{"option":"Amblyopia","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior capsule opacification","bool":true},{"option":"Retinal detachment","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Regarding metabolic disorders associated with congenital cataracts which of the following is correct?","answers":[{"option":"Oil droplet lens opacities develop within the first few weeks of life in patients with galactosemia","bool":true},{"option":"Dense opacities are present in galactosemia","bool":false},{"option":"Mannosidosis is autosomal recessive disorder (AOL) with defacing of alpha-mannosidase","bool":false},{"option":"Exclusion of galactose cannot reverse early lens changes","bool":false},{"option":"Female carriers of Lowe syndrome have visually significant cortical lens opacities","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"What method is used to test visual fields?","answers":[{"option":"Pachymetry","bool":false},{"option":"Perimetry","bool":true},{"option":"Retinoscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Gonioscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Opthalmoscopy","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Chronic dacryocystitis is treated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Oral antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Dacrocystorhinostomy","bool":true},{"option":"Probing and syringing","bool":false},{"option":"Local steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Local antibiotics","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Conjunctival scarring is seen in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Allergic conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Adenoviral conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Trachoma","bool":true},{"option":"Viral conjunctivitis","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Short-term use of topical steroids is indicated in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Acanthamoebal keratitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute allergic conjunctivitis","bool":true},{"option":"Acute bacterial conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Fungal keratitis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic allergic conjunctivitis","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Nerve fiber damage in glaucoma is assessed by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Pachymetry","bool":false},{"option":"Biometry","bool":false},{"option":"Optical coherence tomography","bool":true},{"option":"Perimetry","bool":false},{"option":"Fundoscopy","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Laser peripheral iridotomy is performed in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Neovascular glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Acute angle-closure glaucoma","bool":true},{"option":"Secondary glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Combined mechanism glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Open angle glaucoma","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Glaucoma is a disease of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Disease of bipolar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Disease of nerve fiber layer","bool":false},{"option":"Optic neuropathy","bool":true},{"option":"Disease of photoreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Disease of ganglion cells","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is least likely to be a predisposing factor for acute angle-closure glaucoma?","answers":[{"option":"Shallow anterior chamber","bool":false},{"option":"Small corneal diameter","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes mellitus","bool":true},{"option":"Small eye","bool":false},{"option":"Hypermetropia","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 25-year-old woman comes to the eye clinic with complaints of a painless swelling on her right upper lid for 4 months. The visual acuity of both eyes is 6/6. Which of the following glands is involved in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Lacrimal glands","bool":false},{"option":"Eyelash follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Gland of Moll","bool":false},{"option":"Meibomian gland","bool":true},{"option":"Gland of Zeis","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 65-year-old male with a history of diabetes and proliferative diabetic retinopathy comes for a follow-up visit to the ophthalmologist. He complains of decreased vision in both eyes. Visual acuity is 6/36 in the right eye and 6/24 in the left eye. Which of the following is a sign of proliferative diabetic retinopathy seen on fundus examination?","answers":[{"option":"Neovascularization at the disc","bool":true},{"option":"Hard exudates","bool":false},{"option":"Cotton wool spots","bool":false},{"option":"Macular edema","bool":false},{"option":"Dot blot hemorrhages","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Itching is a characteristic symptom of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Trachoma","bool":false},{"option":"Fungal conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Allergic conjunctivitis","bool":true},{"option":"Viral conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial conjunctivitis","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Herbert's pits are pathognomic of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Fungal conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Viral conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Trachoma","bool":true},{"option":"Allergic conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial conjunctivitis","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"What is the main complication of trachoma?","answers":[{"option":"Stye","bool":false},{"option":"Dacrocystitis","bool":false},{"option":"Chalazion","bool":false},{"option":"Iritis","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal opacity","bool":true}]},{"id":31,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"What is the latest drug of choice for trachoma?","answers":[{"option":"Tetracycline","bool":false},{"option":"Ofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Azithromycin","bool":true},{"option":"Erythromycin","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"What are Herbert's pits?","answers":[{"option":"Lymphoid follicles","bool":false},{"option":"Cicatrization of follicles","bool":true},{"option":"Active follicles","bool":false},{"option":"Limbal papillae","bool":false},{"option":"Local corneal opacities","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Why is preauricular lymphadenopathy a common finding in conjunctivitis?","answers":[{"option":"Protozoa","bool":false},{"option":"Bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"Autoimmunity","bool":false},{"option":"Viruses","bool":true},{"option":"Fungi","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 40-year-old male came to the eye clinic with complaints of pain, watering, and decreased vision in the right eye for the past 4 days. Visual acuity in the right eye is 6/12 and 6/6 in the left eye. On examination, there is a branching corneal opacity in the right eye. What is the best possible diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acanthamoeba keratitis","bool":false},{"option":"Viral keratitis","bool":true},{"option":"Contact lens related keratitis","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial keratitis","bool":false},{"option":"Fungal keratitis","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 45-year-old male presents to the clinic with complaints of bilateral decreased vision for the past 4 days. He has been on antituberculosis therapy for the past 4 months. Visual acuity is 6/36 bilaterally. The pupillary reaction shows relative afferent pupillary defect (RAPD). What is the best possible diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Toxic optic neuropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Optic neuritis","bool":true},{"option":"Papillitis","bool":false},{"option":"Papilledema","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 60-year-old male with hypertension comes to the clinic with complaints of sudden painless vision loss in his left eye. Visual acuity shows his left eye is Plano positive. He has a relative afferent pupillary defect in the left eye. The fundus of the left eye shows a cherry-red spot on the fovea. What is the best diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Central retinal vein occlusion","bool":false},{"option":"Central retinal artery occlusion","bool":true},{"option":"Tay Sachs disease","bool":false},{"option":"Niemann Pick disease","bool":false},{"option":"Macular hole","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 10-year-old child came to the clinic with complaints of night blindness with irritation and watering in both eyes. On examination, the anterior segment showed bitot spots on the conjunctiva. Which of the following vitamin deficiencies leads to this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin E","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin C","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin A","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin D","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 10-day-old female comes to the pediatric clinic with bilateral eyelid edema with mucopurulent discharge 2 days after her birth. What is the treatment for this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Topical steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Topical antibiotics","bool":true},{"option":"Systemic antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Intravitreal antibiotics","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 40-year-old male comes to the eye clinic after being diagnosed with primary open-angle glaucoma in both eyes. Visual acuity is 6/12 in both eyes. Funduscopy showed a 0.7 cup/disc ratio with nasalization of the vessels. Which of the following drugs is contraindicated in asthmatic patients?","answers":[{"option":"Prostaglandin analogs","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha adrenergic agonists","bool":false},{"option":"Beta blockers","bool":true},{"option":"Osmotic agents","bool":false},{"option":"Carbonic anhydrase inhibitors","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"An 18-year-old male comes to the eye clinic with complaints of a headache and a gradual decrease in vision in both of his eyes. On examination, visual acuity in both eyes is 6/18. He has a refractive error of +2.50DS in both eyes. Fundoscopy reveals both fundi are normal. What is the best possible statement regarding his refractive error?","answers":[{"option":"Light rays converge behind the retina","bool":true},{"option":"Light rays do not focus on the retina due to decrease in accommodation","bool":false},{"option":"Light rays converge in front of the retina","bool":false},{"option":"Light rays of both meridians converge in front of the retina","bool":false},{"option":"Light rays of both meridians converge behind the retina","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which one of the following statements best defines blindness?","answers":[{"option":"Visual acuity less than 3/60 (Snellen)","bool":true},{"option":"Inability to count fingers at 1 metre","bool":false},{"option":"Visual acuity less than 6/60 (Snellen)","bool":false},{"option":"No light perception","bool":false},{"option":"Visual acuity less than 1/60 (Snellen)","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A community in a remote village seeks advice from a public health professional on how to avoid trachoma-related blindness that is rampant in the community. What would be the best advice for this community?","answers":[{"option":"Improved access to healthcare","bool":false},{"option":"Hygiene","bool":false},{"option":"Isolation","bool":false},{"option":"SAFE strategy","bool":true},{"option":"Early treatment","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 45-year-old lady comes to the eye clinic with sudden painful swelling on the medial aspect of the right eye with watering, redness, and discharge. What is the site of inflammation of this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Eyelid","bool":false},{"option":"Cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal sac","bool":true},{"option":"Conjunctiva","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal gland","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 55-year-old male with diabetes comes to the eye clinic with complaints of sudden restriction of eye movement in the right eye in all gazes except laterally with dropping eyelid. Visual acuity is 6/6 in both eyes. Which of the following nerves supplies the lateral rectus muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Third nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Fifth nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Seventh nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Sixth nerve","bool":true}]},{"id":45,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 26-year-old male comes to the eye clinic with complaints of redness in both eyes with watery discharge. On examination, there is preauricular lymphadenopathy. Visual acuity is 6/6 in both eyes. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Adenoviral keratoconjunctivitis","bool":true},{"option":"Acute bacterial conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Vernal keratoconjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Cicatricial conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute allergic conjunctivitis","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 60-year-old male undergoes cataract surgery in the right eye and presents to the eye clinic 2 days later with severe pain, redness, discharge, and decreased vision. Visual acuity in the right eye is 1/60 and the left eye is 6/9. On examination, there is a loss of red reflex in the right eye. What is a possible cause of this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Endophthalmitis","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior capsule opacification","bool":false},{"option":"Central retinal artery occlusion","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 65-year-old male undergoes uncomplicated right eye cataract surgery and presents to the eye clinic 6 months later with complaints of a gradual decrease in vision in the right eye with glares. Corrected visual acuity in the right eye is 6/24 and 6/9 in the left. What is the possible cause of this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Delayed onset postoperative endophthalmitis","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior capsule contraction","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior capsule opacification","bool":true},{"option":"Corneal abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Lens matter in anterior chamber","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 40-year-old female comes to the clinic with sudden painless loss of vision in her right eye for 1 day. Visual acuity is Plano positive in the right eye. On slit-lamp examination, there is corneal edema. Intraocular pressure (IOP) is 40 mm Hg. Which of the following has caused her symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Vitreous hemorrhages","bool":false},{"option":"Primary angle-closure glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Cataract","bool":false},{"option":"Conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Primary open-angle glaucoma","bool":true}]},{"id":49,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 20-year-old male comes to the clinic with a history of trauma in the right eye from a tennis ball. Examination reveals it is a blowout fracture in the right eye. Which of the following is the most common site of blowout fracture of the orbit?","answers":[{"option":"Roof of the orbit","bool":false},{"option":"Medial wall of the orbit","bool":false},{"option":"Floor of the orbit","bool":true},{"option":"Apex of the orbit","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral wall of the orbit","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 4-year-old male presents to the clinic with complaints of medial deviation of both his eyes since the age of 3 years. He has been wearing spectacles for the past year. Which of the following is not included in the assessment of a squint?","answers":[{"option":"Corneal fluorescein staining","bool":true},{"option":"Cover test","bool":false},{"option":"Prism alternate cover test","bool":false},{"option":"Alternate cover test","bool":false},{"option":"Uncover test","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 50-year-old male comes to the eye clinic with a history of blunt trauma to his right eye 4 months ago. He complains of a painful decrease in vision in his right eye. Visual acuity in the right eye is 6/36 and the left eye is 6/6. Slit-lamp examination shows horizontal fluorescein-stained cornea. What could have caused this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal abrasion","bool":true},{"option":"Keratoconus","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal dystrophies","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal perforation","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 4-year-old child comes to the clinic with complaints of fever and malaise for the past 5 days. 2 days ago he suddenly developed severe periorbital swelling of the right eye with proptosis and painful eye movements. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Toxic optic neuropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Cataract","bool":false},{"option":"Orbital cellulitis","bool":true}]},{"id":53,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 65-year-old male comes to the eye clinic with complaints of a painless gradual decrease in vision in both his eyes. Visual acuity is 6/60 in the right eye and 6/36 in the left. Fundoscopy reveals normal fundi in both eyes. What is the possible cause of this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Vitreous hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Primary open angle glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Cataract","bool":true},{"option":"Primary acute angle-closure glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Myopia","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which statement about the sebaceous glands in the fibrous layer of the eyelid is the odd one out?","answers":[{"option":"Embedded in the tarsal plate","bool":false},{"option":"Their ducts open anterior to greyline","bool":true},{"option":"Placed vertically in the tarsal plate","bool":false},{"option":"Usually produces painless cystic swelling when inflamed","bool":false},{"option":"Present little away from the lid margin","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following events occur when a sharp bright light strikes the retina?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperpolarization of presynaptic membrane","bool":true},{"option":"Releasing of glutamate from presynaptic terminal","bool":false},{"option":"Increased intracellular cGMP","bool":false},{"option":"Opening of Na gated channels","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of bipolar cells","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 9-year-old boy complains of difficulty reading the blackboard in school. Examination findings led to a diagnosis of short-sightedness. What lens should be used to correct this refractive error?","answers":[{"option":"Cylindrical lenses","bool":false},{"option":"Biconcave lenses","bool":true},{"option":"Convaxo concave lenses","bool":false},{"option":"Biconvex lenses","bool":false},{"option":"Concavo convex lenses","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 70-year-old man complains of loss of vision in the right half of both eyes after an ischemic stroke. The MRI reveals a hemorrhagic infarct at the level of the midbrain before the lateral geniculate body. Which of the following is a site for this type of lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Optic chiasm","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Geniculo calcrine tract","bool":false},{"option":"Optic tract","bool":true},{"option":"Optic radiation","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"What is the thickest wall of the bony orbit?","answers":[{"option":"Medial wall","bool":false},{"option":"Floor","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral wall","bool":true},{"option":"Apex","bool":false},{"option":"Roof","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following layers of the cornea has no power of regeneration?","answers":[{"option":"Endothelium","bool":false},{"option":"Descemet's membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Bowman's membrane","bool":true},{"option":"Stroma","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelium","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most frequent cause of blindness worldwide?","answers":[{"option":"Cataract","bool":true},{"option":"Corneal opacities","bool":false},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Age related macular degeneration","bool":false},{"option":"Trachoma","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"What is the definition of legal blindness?","answers":[{"option":"No perception of light","bool":false},{"option":"Visual acuity of less than 3/60 (Snellen chart)","bool":true},{"option":"Visual acuity of 6/18 or less (Snellen chart)","bool":false},{"option":"Visual acuity of 5/60 or less (Snellen chart)","bool":false},{"option":"Visual acuity of 6/60 or less (Snellen chart)","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of proptosis in adults?","answers":[{"option":"Orbital teratoma","bool":false},{"option":"Retinoblastoma","bool":false},{"option":"Orbital cellulitis","bool":false},{"option":"Grave ophthalmopathy","bool":true},{"option":"Orbital hemorrhage","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"What is the most common cause of trichiasis?","answers":[{"option":"Trachoma","bool":true},{"option":"Ectropion","bool":false},{"option":"Blepharitis","bool":false},{"option":"Chemical burns","bool":false},{"option":"Keratitis","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following classes of drugs is the first-line treatment for primary open-angle glaucoma?","answers":[{"option":"Beta blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Prostaglandin analogues","bool":true},{"option":"Miotics","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha-2 agonists","bool":false},{"option":"Carbonic anhydrase inhibitors","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most common non-surgical method for treating myopia?","answers":[{"option":"Cylindrical lens","bool":false},{"option":"Laser in situ keratomileusis (LASIK)","bool":false},{"option":"Power lens","bool":false},{"option":"Contact lens","bool":false},{"option":"Glasses","bool":true}]},{"id":66,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is a binocular conjugate movement of the eyes?","answers":[{"option":"Excycloduction","bool":false},{"option":"Intorsion","bool":false},{"option":"Version","bool":true},{"option":"Duction","bool":false},{"option":"Vergence","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following best describes blindness?","answers":[{"option":"Visual field less than 60 degrees","bool":false},{"option":"Visual field less than 40 degrees","bool":false},{"option":"Visual field less than 50 degrees","bool":false},{"option":"Visual field less than 10 degrees","bool":true},{"option":"Visual field less than 30 degrees","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following stains is most commonly used for the diagnosis of corneal pathologies?","answers":[{"option":"Fluorescein","bool":true},{"option":"Lissamine green","bool":false},{"option":"Indocyanine green","bool":false},{"option":"Trypan blue","bool":false},{"option":"Rose bengal","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 23-year-old patient presents in the outpatient clinic with a complaint of diplopia for 5 days. On examination, there is a marked limitation in right abduction. What is the likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Myasthenia gravis","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth nerve palsy","bool":false},{"option":"Seventh nerve palsy","bool":false},{"option":"Third nerve palsy","bool":false},{"option":"Sixth nerve palsy","bool":true}]},{"id":70,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"In which of the following conditions pupillary dilatation is seen?","answers":[{"option":"Use of pilocarpine","bool":false},{"option":"At night","bool":true},{"option":"At daytime","bool":false},{"option":"Use of morphine","bool":false},{"option":"At accomodation","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 35-year-old patient presents in the outpatient clinic with redness in one eye and vesicular eruptions around the eye and on her forehead for one day. What is the likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Vernal conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes zoster ophthalmicus","bool":true},{"option":"Herpes simplex infection","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior uveitis","bool":false},{"option":"Erysipelas","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following best describes the lesions of herpes simplex virus keratitis?","answers":[{"option":"Disciform keratitis with increased corneal sensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Ring abscess with corneal melting","bool":false},{"option":"Geographical ulcer with increased corneal sensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Filamentous keratitis with decreased corneal sensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Dendritic ulcer with decreased corneal sensitivity","bool":true}]},{"id":73,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is not associated with the long-term use of topical steroids?","answers":[{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Cataract","bool":false},{"option":"Ocular tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Uveitis","bool":true},{"option":"Fungal eye infections","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is not a feature of diabetic retinopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Drusen spots","bool":true},{"option":"Microaneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Dot and blot hemorrhages","bool":false},{"option":"Hard exudates","bool":false},{"option":"Soft exudates","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is not an antimetabolite drug?","answers":[{"option":"Methotrexate","bool":false},{"option":"Mercaptopurine","bool":false},{"option":"Infliximab","bool":true},{"option":"Hydroxyurea","bool":false},{"option":"Fluorouracil","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is true about pupils?","answers":[{"option":"They dilate with convergence of the eyes","bool":false},{"option":"They dilate in dark","bool":true},{"option":"They dilate in light","bool":false},{"option":"Pilocarpine dilates pupil","bool":false},{"option":"Dilator pupilae is supplied by cholinergic fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is not correct regarding basal cell carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"80% of cases involve the head and neck region","bool":false},{"option":"It is non-malignant tumor","bool":true},{"option":"20% of cases involve the eyelid only","bool":false},{"option":"It is the most common human malignancy in the elderly","bool":false},{"option":"Majority of cases occur in the lower eyelid","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding intraocular pressure?","answers":[{"option":"Resistance to flow of aqueous humor through trabecular meshwork is the cause of glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Normal variation throughout the day is 8 mmHg","bool":true},{"option":"Intraocular pressure of 25-30 mmHg is diagnostic of glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Intraocular pressure of 25-30 mmHg for prolonged periods can lead to visual impairment","bool":false},{"option":"Intraocular pressure is measured by tonometry","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is the point of strongest vitreoretinal attachment?","answers":[{"option":"Optic disc","bool":false},{"option":"Equator","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior surface of lens","bool":false},{"option":"Pars plana (ora serrata)","bool":true},{"option":"Macula","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most appropriate regarding posterior vitreous detachment?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"It is not related to advanced age","bool":false},{"option":"The separation of posterior vitreous can produce a hole in the posterior pole","bool":false},{"option":"The separation of posterior vitreous from inner limiting membrane of retina","bool":false},{"option":"The complications can produce sub-hyaloid hemorrhage","bool":true}]},{"id":81,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of red eye?","answers":[{"option":"Foreign body","bool":false},{"option":"Uveitis","bool":false},{"option":"Keratitis","bool":false},{"option":"Conjunctivitis","bool":true},{"option":"Blepharitis","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most appropriate statement regarding normal tension glaucoma?","answers":[{"option":"It may be associated with nocturnal sleep apnea syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Calcium channel blockers have no role in the treatment","bool":false},{"option":"Medical therapy is usually effective","bool":false},{"option":"There is no inherited predisposition","bool":false},{"option":"Visual field loss does not progress as disease progresses","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 14-year-old boy presents with recurrent attacks of itching, lacrimation, and burning of the eyes. The symptoms worsen during the summer season. On examination, papillary hypertrophy is seen in both eyes. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Vernal keratoconjunctivitis","bool":true},{"option":"Phlyctenular conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Viral conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Perennial allergic conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Seasonal allergic conjunctivitis","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following methods is not implicated in the management of squint?","answers":[{"option":"Penalization","bool":false},{"option":"Disinsertion","bool":true},{"option":"Muscle resection","bool":false},{"option":"Botulinum toxin injection","bool":false},{"option":"Corrective glasses","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is an appropriate description of amblyopia?","answers":[{"option":"Defect in visual acuity","bool":true},{"option":"Defect in visual field","bool":false},{"option":"Defect in central vision","bool":false},{"option":"Defect in color vision","bool":false},{"option":"Defect in accommodation","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 1-year-old boy undergoes probing for the treatment of congenital nasolacrimal duct obstruction. During the procedure, a probe is passed into the lacrimal canaliculus until a hard structure is felt and this guides the turning of the probe downwards. Which of the following is the most likely concerned structure?","answers":[{"option":"Lacrimal sac","bool":true},{"option":"Common canaliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Nasolacrimal duct","bool":false},{"option":"Vertical canaliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Horizontal canaliculus","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 56-year-old patient presents to the clinic with sudden painless unilateral loss of vision for the past 6 hours. His past medical history is significant for uncontrolled hypertension. What is the most likely cause in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Branched retinal artery occlusion","bool":false},{"option":"Angle closure glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Central retinal vein occlusion","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior uveitis","bool":false},{"option":"Retinal detachment","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following mechanisms occur during the accommodation reflex?","answers":[{"option":"Divergence and pupillary dilatation","bool":false},{"option":"Adduction and convergence","bool":false},{"option":"Convergence and pupillary constriction","bool":true},{"option":"Divergence and pupillary constriction","bool":false},{"option":"Convergence and pupillary dilatation","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"A 4-year-old boy presents with an outward deviation of the right eye for 5 months. The deviation is not present at all times and manifests in times of stress and exposure to bright light. What is the likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Intermittent esotropia","bool":false},{"option":"Intermittent exotropia","bool":true},{"option":"Congenital exotropia","bool":false},{"option":"Intermittent exophoria","bool":false},{"option":"Paralytic exotropia","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is(are) the cardinal features of corneal pathology?","answers":[{"option":"Pain and photophobia","bool":true},{"option":"Flashes and floaters","bool":false},{"option":"Mucopurulent discharge","bool":false},{"option":"Itching and burning","bool":false},{"option":"Painless loss of vision","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following methods is used for the measurement of corneal thickness?","answers":[{"option":"Keratometry","bool":false},{"option":"Tonometry","bool":false},{"option":"Gonioscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal topography","bool":false},{"option":"Pachymetry","bool":true}]},{"id":92,"info":"4th-year/eye/2021","question":"Which of the following is an appropriate statement regarding age-related macular degeneration (ARMD)?","answers":[{"option":"Dry ARMD is treated by photocoagulation","bool":false},{"option":"Wet ARMD has good prognosis","bool":false},{"option":"Wet ARMD is the most common form","bool":false},{"option":"Wet ARMD occurs due to drusen formation","bool":false},{"option":"Wet ARMD is treated by anti-vascular endothelial growth factor","bool":true}]}]
export default arr